Right now, crypto wallets are the most credible attempt to becoming the super app of the new
internet because they've started with the most difficult thing to build into a super app,
which is finance and money management. A lot of applications in social try to become super apps
by adding on payments or finance as an afterthought. Crypto wallets have started there as a default.
Crypto is basically the kind of black hole that's absorbing everything that's going on in finance.
It's going to be very difficult to stop the momentum around all the network effects there.
If you're trying to recreate everything from scratch, it's going to be difficult to compete.
Crypto wallets are basically the way that people interact with crypto today. They're sort of the
interface, the first touch point, your window to the world. Brandon, you're building Phantom.
How do you think about crypto wallets? What they are and what they've evolved into?
Yeah, crypto wallets today are this tool to help users discover and interact with this world
that's been developing in the on-chain ecosystem. It wasn't actually always the wallet that people
would reach to first when they're trying to use crypto. When the infrastructure was a lot less
developed and it was a lot harder to use blockchain directly, we have centralized exchanges who help
users actually get access to Bitcoin, Ether, other cryptocurrencies like that. But as it's
become more developed, it becomes our role more and more to present everything that's going on
to the user in a really nice package shop window, which looks more and more like the consumer finance
app of the future. We've inherited this terminology of calling these things wallets
since the early days of crypto. But I wonder, is that the best analogy that people should
have in mind for using this piece of technology? Or is there a better way to think about what purpose
these tools are serving? I think, yes, and no, the wallet still very much at its core is about
the management and custody, safe keeping of assets and currency, much like what you would
expect of a physical wallet. But because your wallet is in this digital form and the world of
on-chain ecosystems have been more and more performant and capable, the wallet has become
a lot more of a tool for doing things with your crypto more than just kind of keeping it in one
place and holding it. I think the browser analogy is a little bit too broad in mind mind. I think
wallet is still pretty good in that. I do think the biggest use cases for crypto are financial in
nature. So I think browser is a little bit too broad. Wallet is still actually pretty decent,
I think, but thinking about it a little bit more of the consumer finance platform.
I think all the wallets started from the same place where wallet was a very apt term because the
job was for the wallet to be a key manager, to store and to manage your private keys and for
you to custody your assets. It allowed you to prove the assets that you owned and authorized
transactions. And then that was like V0 of the wallet. And now we've had V1 of the wallet, which is
more of an on-chain money manager and consumer finance platform. So now you can trade, you can
stay, you can lend, you can borrow, you can make payments all within the wallet itself. And then
where you start to see things bifurcate, Robert, like you mentioned, is some wallets are sticking
out their territory in building out this consumer finance platform. Others are becoming developer
platforms and super apps and are leading more into social or gaming or other features. And that's
where you're seeing the space fragment or move away from the traditional sense of the word wallet.
So, Jay, I'm glad you jumped in here. So you've been working on a post about how you believe crypto
wallets are poised to be the super apps of this new decentralized internet. This has long been
sort of a holy grail for the consumer internet economy, like who is going to be the next super app
or be the super app. Canonically, in the East, it was WeChat in China, but nothing quite replicated
that in the West. Tell me how you're thinking about that super app thesis that has sort of long been
a part of people's investment ideas. Right now, crypto wallets are the most
credible attempt to becoming the super app of the new internet, because they've started with,
I think, what is typically the most difficult thing to build into a super app, which is finance
and money management. I think we've seen a lot of applications and social try to become super apps
by adding on payments or finance as an afterthought. And those things are really difficult because they
require a lot of user trust. It's heavily regulated. There's a lot of infrastructure that you have to
build. It has to be really, really performant for it to work for users and for it to be multiplayer.
Crypto wallets have started there as a default. And I think it's much easier to build trust with
the user having become their core money management and finance platform in this new internet and
then expand outwards into social, into gaming. Like WeChat, their killer feature was messaging.
I think for wallets right now, it's finance. It's trading. Nothing in crypto has really achieved
better product market fit than trading and creating digital assets, whether it's NFTs,
whether it's meme coins, whether it's the majors, whether it's on-spot exchanges or perps.
There's like seemingly endless demand to trade and speculate and participate in DeFi. So I think
having started from finance and then expanding into other verticals is a much easier thing to do
than vice versa as evidenced by snap cash, as evidenced by meta's attempt to get into finance
and payments and Instagram and so many, so many others that are failed attempts at super apps.
So you're drawing this distinction between sort of two ways to go about achieving the super app
vision. One is the sort of what had been regarded as the tried and true path or at least like the
proven path that WeChat took. You start with messaging and then you add on all these other
features like financial services and such. But what you're saying is that there's actually this
other approach that people are now exploring because the messaging to finance and other services
has not panned out the same way in the West that it had with WeChat in the East. And that maybe
there's this other way you could go about exploring the idea maze where you start with the financial
aspects, the money management and those services, and then back yourself into all the other things
that a consumer might expect from a super app. Yeah, exactly. I mean, one of the beauties of
crypto is permissionless innovation and there's two kind of paths that we've seen. One is you have
wallets like the base app, maybe the world app, and even Farkaster as a native wallet, and they're
effectively developer platforms where they are providing a mini app SDK and they are encouraging
third party developers to build apps and features that users can interact with on top of the basic
financial things that people are now accustomed to doing in crypto. And then I would argue that
Phantom is maybe taking a bit more opinionated approach, building out features that they see
doing really well in crypto, whether that's hyper liquid perbs, whether that's social feeds,
and they build that into the core interface of Phantom itself. The beauty of crypto is like any
time one of these things does really well. It's permissionless for these wallets to become a front
end for that protocol and you can present whatever that use case or feature is in a really consumer
friendly way. Maybe something I'll clarify is that although I do think that crypto and certainly
Phantom's position as a wallet positions it very nicely to potentially become this sort of all
encompassing super app platform. I will say that's not something that we are really have our aisle
on the ball right now. For us it's all about focusing on actually achieving that consumer
finance platform vision and decisively cutting things all around that so that we're actually
really nailing that because crypto still has a long way to go in terms of being used as that
finance platform. But to Jay's point I do think that our ability to really unlock the true powers
of crypto being this internet first global permissionless ecosystem is going to give us
basically the tools that we need to achieve this consumer finance platform vision and then
potentially parlay that into something a bit broader. Let's talk more deeply about what you're
doing at Phantom. For people who are unfamiliar with it what makes Phantom stand out? What differentiates
it from all of the other wallet options that are at people's disposal? Yeah I think when you
boil it down it comes down to placing a heavy emphasis on the user experience as a whole
usability. I think a lot of people conflate UI with UX and just think about what an app looks like
on the screen but I think what really separates us is our ability to actually think holistically
about the user journey how they first hear about crypto how they get educated through that how they
onboard things like customer support and all that. Another thing that separates us is our ability
to navigate on chain trends be where people want to be at the right time. We obviously were very
early to Solana and more recently took pretty big bat on hyper liquid as well. I think what Phantom
does is they have done a great job at being impeninated about what people are doing on chain
and then taking those experiences and making them available to users in as few clicks or taps as
possible and with as much delight and fun and stickiness as possible building that experience
and having first class security is what really I think enables them to build a ton of user trust.
In other words what you both are saying here is that Brandon that you guys at Phantom you are trying
to go where the people are and follow what they're doing rather than try to force them into some
behavior that you're not seeing them already participate in you're kind of like you see the
heat and you're seeking it. Yeah there's a lot of things that people already really like to do
in crypto and I think being super opinionated about how to present those experiences in the most
accessible way possible and also safest way possible is part of that secret sauce that helps us
retain users and keep them coming back day after day. Tell us about the Phantom story you mentioned
that you guys started launching with Solana early on that was a sort of contrarian bet at the time
certainly in the wake of FTX's implosion there were a lot of questions about that entire ecosystem
and how it would fare so give us the the short history of why you started there and how you got
to where you are today. I got my start in crypto back in 2017 and joined at early stage crypto startup
D5 startup called zero x that was sort of the sort of ICO white paper era of crypto. That was a really
early decentralized exchange. Yeah that's where I cut my teeth in crypto for about four years from
2017-2021. And before that by the way just to not short thrift yourself before that you
worked at Twitter. Yeah before before jumping into crypto yeah got my start as a software engineer
and builder at Twitter 2013-2017 that's where I really learned how to build apps for like massive
scale massive global scale and my co-founder Chris early Facebook employee very similar
experience. Three co-founders me Chris Matyska we all found our way to zero x during that time
you know pretty crazy saw the rise of Uniswap compound D5 summer all those types of things and
yeah through that time basically realized a couple things so one the wallet is an extremely
key part of infrastructure for the entire ecosystem. If the wallet's not really doing its job then
it really has like a decelerating effect for everyone else because when you're an application
builder which we were at zero x a lot of the onus of onboarding confirming a transaction or sort of
like the checkout it relies on the wallet. Menomask at that time being the biggest wallet people would
use on Ethereum it really depends on them doing their job so we thought that this wallet has this
huge responsibility but no one was really stepping up to the plate and taking that responsibility
seriously at least over the number of years that we had been working in the Ethereum ecosystem
and so decided hey actually our expertise is in these consumer internet apps we think that this
usability problem can actually be solved at this wallet layer and we can actually help
that's the highest leverage place that we can apply ourselves to actually accelerate the adoption
of crypto so that that was first insight and then the second one was the world is moving to this
more multi chain format. My very first indication of that was actually Binance Smart Chain in 2020
which was one of the first non ETH L1 chains. Seeing that actually gained serious traction
really opened a lot of people's eyes myself included that hey there is a whole world out there
of users who have not touched crypto yet and there is an appetite to use something that's
faster and cheaper than ETH L1 so I think combining some of those insights together we decided hey
we're going to create a multi chain metamask competitor but the way that we were going to do
it was to basically try to leapfrog the technology and skate to where the puck is going and grab our
own home turf on an up-and-coming ecosystem that we thought had what it took to really surpass
Ethereum. So you were like Ethereum's taken they've got metamask Binance has come up they're doing
their own thing where else can we play? We initially got attracted to Solano because we found that
from a Valley's perspective we were much more aligned especially as builders coming out of Silicon
Valley and more traditional tech companies so yeah you know we found that we really jived well
with Raj and totally spent a lot of time with them and then decided hey yeah we're going to
basically choose Solano as our horse we sort of know how it panned out but there were some moments
where it was kind of you know it was kind of rough yeah well so the idea was choose Solano's
our horse you know become the metamask Solano and then evolve the wallet into a multi chain wallet
with the thesis that hey wallets are becoming the entry point into crypto but what we didn't
anticipate was like how hard Solano would pop off basically over the last couple of years and how
quickly people would respond to how the fast and cheap transactions actually enabled this very
smooth user experience but yes obviously it's heads up and downs you mentioned FTX you know I have a
little bit of a contrary intake on FTX maybe it's not true but you know that's maybe one of the best
things that could have happened to Solano in the sense that it was sort of a canonical
like mass purging event that left only the true believers essentially of the ecosystem
and formed like a super genuine core that you know precipitated a very genuine culture and
ecosystem of builders that's sort of all you know chewed glass together I think they gave you the
jet fuel to like go for this next like which we just saw and it was continuing to experience in
2024 or 2025 you know obviously we do everything we can to make sure that people are having a
good time when they're using Solano and it's been a great ecosystem to build in what doesn't kill
you makes you stronger yeah definitely from an investor perspective I'll attest that like when
crypto is booming and really hot there are a lot of tourists just across the stack like there's a
lot of tourists investors a lot of tourists retail consumers builders and anyone that was building on
Solano post FTX was very serious and very committed to Solano and building on Solano for a very
particular set of reasons that if you were chewing glass in that time there was a load of credibility
that you kind of gained for sticking around and a lot of those folks reap the benefits yeah and
we're seeing that now it's definitely paid off and phantom you know although it has been closely
associated with Solano you guys have branched out far beyond it and you are now multi-chain
yeah I'm really happy that we were able to invest in doing that multi-chain transformation back in
2023 although it was actually very unfortunately timed actually where we had been developing it
through the period of 2022 FTX happened and then we kind of had to say like oh hey we're going multi-chain
but i'm glad we really did the hard thing and got over those hurdles because it has allowed us to
actually branch off into our own standalone brand that people recognize as not just the front end
just Solano and more recently they're one of the top front ends for trading purpose on hyperlooker
so you mentioned perps a few times let's talk a little bit about perps or perpetual futures
and what they are why you've decided to add them to your wallet and yeah what people can do with
them you know simply put perps are a new type of financial derivative that people can trade so
similar to options or classic futures they allow folks to bet on the price movement of an asset
without actually buying the underlying asset so you can say i think bitcoin's going to go up i
want to profit off of that i think big one's going down i want to place that trade and so it allows
you to go longer short and it actually allows you also to place those trades with leverage 2x5x and
in some cases larger and what's really interesting is that conceptually perps are actually a lot easier
to understand and grasp than options trading but they've typically had this reputation for being
very much an advanced instrument that doesn't really cater towards retail users and so
we found a really interesting opportunity to basically apply our expertise in usability
and sort of really creating dialed in user experiences specifically for a retail user base
and apply that to perps we thought that hey actually the underlying concepts here are not that
hard to understand in a lot of ways much easier than options let's actually try to do the hard work
making that easier for a retail audience to access a specific example of that is in a lot of
perp trading interfaces you see these words like take profit and stop loss i think phantom you guys
say auto close versus opening position you can auto close which just makes it a lot more intuitive
for retail versus thinking about these terms that are a bit more native to people who are
financially and crypto savvy yeah there's tons of those little micro interactions that we've kind
of just stopped and had a second think about and just kind of thought about from first principles
you know another thing that we've added that's quite interesting is also this user onboarding
education tutorial system that helps users understand what they're doing and then also
specify their risk profile hey i'm generally low risk or actually i do want to go for high risk
and then actually set some of the defaults around that choice that the user made i actually went
through the flow earlier today and it was super slick and simple to kind of understand and also
slot yourself into whichever risk tolerance you you want for yourself while it's have come so far
in the last four to five years we've come from like 12 word seed phrases and a point where there was
no way for the average consumer to know what was happening when they were interacting with a given
smart contract and you know if you're a newbie you would effectively be signing a transaction
sometimes and hoping you didn't wake up the next morning with your wallet drained now we have like
the ux and onboarding improved to a point where we have social login because we have distributed
key management protocols we have transaction simulation spam filters and like token safety
ratings we've got past keys we've got biometrics we have smart wallets like you guys have usernames
if you're creating a new profile where for the longest you as a user were just like a string of
numbers and characters and you know if you are my mom you have no idea why you are zero x four
five y three f and we have all these improvements on just like wallet ux that have made crypto so much
more easy to interact with like i think we don't give enough credit to wallet teams for making it
a million times easier to interact with everything that we can do on jane yeah it is funny i mean it
kind of echoes some things that happened with the evolution of browsers you know and going from
ip addresses to having sort of a domain name system where you can enter into your url bar you know
these sort of like human readable names to go to your destination all sorts of cryptographic
improvements so that like people can't steal your credit card information if you're buying something
online like it's cool to see these sorts of upgrades and improvements happen in crypto and in the wallet
context like sort of speedrunning things you know happening in a much more condensed time frame
yeah i mean we've put a lot of effort into it and sent a lot of time investing and obviously these
are experienced originally the app was a browser extension uh we quickly follow that up with a mobile
app in beginning of 2022 and now it's a we consider ourselves very much of a mobile first product
a perfect experience that we're just talking about it was mobile first as well and you know
that's just where crypto is going generally let's linger on this perps thing for a minute you're
obviously catering to a particular kind of user who is interested in participating in the financial
aspects of crypto like a classic use of perps is like you said you're betting on whether the price
of something is going to go up or down and you can use leverage to do it that is something that
speculators love but if crypto is going to sort of include a whole big wide audience of people
that particular thing might be not for all comers yeah totally you know if you think about
the consumer finance platforms that people use today Robinhood square cash Venmo etc sort of take
the union of all the different financial activities that people like to do you get
investing speculating you get payments saving storing holding and so those are some of the
areas that we're thinking about and working on but those are things that you should expect
to be able to do in phantom you know all in one so you're basically saying there are other areas
that you're exploring that you think a wider audience might potentially find valuable yeah well
I think it's certainly going to help make phantom and crypto part of their everyday lives that's
where I think payments can actually really turn a corner sort of in this wave so earlier on in
the conversation we were talking about the landscape of wallets that are out there you know you've
got sort of metamask in early ethereum wallet relative newcomers like coinbase wallet which
has rebranded to base after their L2 and you have newer sorts of wallets for maybe power users like
rabby what separates phantom from those others how are you sort of staking out a different kind of
part of the universe than the other wallets that are out there we don't really think much about
metamask when i'm thinking about like setting the north star competition for the company we're
thinking a lot more like players like robin did actually not even thinking about the company
as a wallet necessarily and more as this consumer finance platform but fueled by the on-chain
economy the great thing about wallets is of all the ones you mentioned there's nothing stopping
a user from using those simultaneously like you can enter your seed phrase and you'll see the
exact same amount of money that you see on phantom that you would on coinbase wallet assuming they
support the same chains as you would on metamask as you would on rabby as you would on trust or
anything the wallets are really competing for like a user's trust and their belief in the security
and the features that are built into the wallet and convenience like of the things that i want
to do on chain which of these wallets gives me the best experience right because at the end of the
day you can still use all of these wallets simultaneously yeah yeah that's a really great
point when you're using wallets you can import all that very simply just by entering your seed
phrase and you can bring all that information and data with you which is really kind of a cool
difference between the web 2 world and the web 3 world yeah that's sort of the beauty of being
built on top of these open protocols is that it gives the user a lot of freedom of choice
and allows competition in the market to really benefit the end consumer but i will say that
despite the fact that it is theoretically easy for users to move in between wallets it's actually
not something that i've seen users do that often when it has to do with finances money people they're
scared to do something they really gravitate towards brands that they trust and feel are safe
usually the wallets that they start with they build that sort of trust relationship with and so
my experience of actually interestingly anecdotally found wallets to be quite sticky in that sense
i remember i think it was maybe late 21 or 22 one of the things that really built a bunch of like
goodwill with phantom for me was seeing the transaction simulation for the first time
and the the browser extension like i was interacting with some smart contract and it very clearly
explained what was going on in green was what would i receive and the red was what was leaving my
wallet it made it really clear and simple and easy to understand and i was like these guys get it
and they presented it in a way that would make it so much more helpful for anyone who is first
getting on chain to use these products and that goodwill compounds and then you have things
later like the haptic feedback when you're executing a trade and you look at it and you see you've
made some money and it's green and the font is really big and you're like this is really fun
that this is a delightful experience and i want to come back and do this again tomorrow i'd love to
know Brandon what your process is for engineering those moments and for having this emphasis on
usability and UX especially in an area where people have long decried the UX and crypto and
particularly in wallets yeah there's certainly a process aspect to it we do do things like user
experience testing for example where we do actually put things in front of users and watch how they
interact and things like that but a big part of it is creating this product centric product led
culture where ideas can flow from the design team not just the engineering team or the sales
team or something like that everything is very user centric and so it kind of flows quite naturally
from that let me ask you this then what is the hardest challenge in creating a crypto wallet app
i think the hardest challenge has been choosing what not to do in crypto especially there's so
much going on that really our job is actually quite similar to an investor where it's like
developing a very good bullshit detector and like intuition for how trends are going to develop to
literally place bats of resources and capital towards yeah the biggest challenge is like
how to navigate the trends such that we're not chasing what is just the flash in the pan and that
has gotten increasingly more difficult and staying really truly long-term thinking especially when
there is a lot of money to be made in trend chasing and you see folks doing it for sure and just
recognizing that sometimes those short-term gains are not worth the damage long-term damage
to the brand for example or like making those types of trade-offs what are you investing in
where are you placing those resources for whatever trends may come in the future well definitely a
couple different areas swapping and trading those are some of the bread and butter core interactions
that people do on crypto so always investing there obviously perps hyper liquids also very
interesting and dynamic ecosystem and environment social is something that we've also been experimenting
with that we're going to be investing in more and more the way that we think about social is more
in terms of taking things that people already like to do like trading for example and help
supercharge it with network effects using social mechanics not necessarily bringing
messaging to the app or bringing social media posts to the app but it's more about infusing
what people already like to do in the app with social mechanics make that concrete for us what
exactly do you mean yeah so there is literally a tab in the app where you click on it and it shows
you all of your folks that you have followed their most recent actions on the app so for example
my friend at Nick he bought Solana and you know he has an unrealized gain of x percent there's
some light reactions that people can do like thumbs up part or whatever that helped the sort of
discovery algorithm like surface things that people are engaging with you scroll down you might
see some more generic network activity like six whales participated in this prediction market or
something like that scroll down and then you see hey five my friends they just participated in this
perps product and so that really helps supercharge the entire crypto ecosystem by helping folks
discover the next thing to do that's the discovery problems been a huge issue in crypto generally
where people get into one thing and there's no golden path to figure out what the next thing to do is
it's usually some amalgamation of like find the right people to follow on twitter or get on
discourse or something like that and usually that's to find some recommendation of what
coin to trade next or what dap to use and so we can bring those recommendations directly in the app
that's kind of concretely what i'm talking about yeah this sort of parallels some features that
other consumer fintech apps have done in the past you know venmo got very popular with their
sort of social activity feed you could see who was paying who you know who's going out to dinner
and all sorts of things like that and then kind of etoro came in the mix i think early on with like
a social feed like a robin hood style thing but you could see what people were betting on
so you're incorporating these sorts of elements drawing from more from the consumer finance world
and adding those features over rather than maybe from like the pure social networking social media
world like a twitter or facebook or something like that yeah i think i think the venmo comparison is
is pretty close in structure it feels like this alive network you can see what everyone's doing
but because the payments angle is so one-dimensional it just didn't end up like crossing that
humpboards like really became like entertainment but because the on-chain ecosystem is so diverse
and there's so many different things going on obviously on top of payments there's the trading
prediction markets anything that can be born on crypto can have a representation in this sort of
like social discovery feed so that is the out division for it and how it's very much a feature
that multiplies everything else that's going on i think increasingly trading and i guess investing
are becoming like entertainment products and so i think that's why it's so important when you
have a social feed because trading with your friends is more fun and might drive you to do
more trading and then let's say you layer on the fact that all this is on-chain you have
programmable money brand then just hundred x2 coin and maybe i go trade that and i make money on it
and then i want to deposit my profits into a vault where i'm going to earn some yield
like then i'm bundling this thing where i'm having fun and i'm managing my finances
and that is a really really powerful and sticky product and i'm doing it with my friends like
that's really cool and that's something that has never really been possible until the last few
years yeah that's a great point and and Brandon you had mentioned like your comp is Robinhood
which sort of started with stock trading and then they've entered into crypto you guys started with
crypto and where do you go from there it's all about doubling down tripling down on crypto
crypto is basically the kind of black hole that's absorbing everything that's going on in finance
and that's the direction that Robinhood and most traffic companies are going right how do i get
into crypto and how do i get exposure to like all the excitement our angle is always going to be like
how do we harness the power of crypto and on-chain ecosystems to really supercharge
the app and meet fraud competitors like one big thing is truly being able to access a global
audience that's something that most of the companies Robinhood included has had difficulties
doing but yeah i do genuinely believe that the open open and permissionless and global nature of
it it's going to be very difficult to stop the momentum around all the network effects there
if you're trying to recreate everything from scratch it's going to be difficult to compete
obviously you know totally and in the slana world there's this big meme of internet capital markets
how far along are we toward achieving that vision you know i think we're getting
pretty close there's all different vectors think about how close we're getting there's the technology
and the scale there's the mainstream acceptance mainstream institutional acceptance and the trends
are definitely accelerating together i mean things are getting more and more digital and becoming
more and more online and this is kind of getting to some apologies digital state stuff but like
you actually are seeing factions of online communities who have true like geopolitical power
this is a balaji serena vassen who yeah you know wrote a book the network state and formerly was
a GP over here also i think people don't necessarily appreciate the accelerating nature of technology
like compounding nature then once you once you throw an ai and all of that you can get there pretty
quick i'm glad you mentioned ai we had elia polasukin the co-founder of near on our show you know one
thing that he was saying that really stuck with me is this idea that he could imagine a world where
apps and websites kind of go away and where everything is sort of mediated by ai agents
i wonder what your take is on that thesis and whether you're planning for a world that could
look like that yes it remains to be seen how ai is going to shape how consumers use internet products
obviously there was the i found moment where things got shifted to this mobile form factor
and that that had really huge implications for all industries yeah that was the leap from websites
to apps app first mobile first for ai it's not exactly clear to me yeah how it's really going
to change things whether you're going to have some ai agent for everything you do it's auto
generating you a ui or something like every one time you want to do something that that seems a
little bit too futuristic i think and then i think when you layer on also touching on what
we were talking about earlier this whole trust aspect especially with finances i think you may
see a little bit of a slower uptake potentially of folks trusting agents with their finances that
being said i do think in a world where ai agents are performing financial transactions the obvious
choice for them to interact on the internet with money is by using crypto it's just the most
frictionless low cost and like internet native borderless medium of exchange so just by sheer law
of physics i don't see a world where like agents are not using crypto as their primary transaction
vehicle i like it will just take i feel like it's at least a couple or a few years out perhaps the
most obvious opportunity for wallets in the context of ai is curating and kind of like editorializing
the apps or protocols that are made available in the the wallet ui itself kind of like tiktok
decides what we watch and spotify decides what we hear there is maybe an opportunity where users
can opt into a wallet deciding like what lending protocol do you use maybe we move towards this
abstraction of protocols that are all integrated into the wallet and maybe the best wallet is the
one that does the best job and has the best trained models on being able to curate that for a given
user given their you know their familiarity with crypto their on chain history their risk tolerance
their preferences all these sets for conditions and that's probably somewhere in between where we
are now and an ili is vision of like agents just fully transacting on our behalf i think
some things that look so obvious are actually still very far away from most people even knowing
what that is that's actually a little bit of a sometimes a drawback of being so deep it's like
it's hard to really step out of that and get that perspective so wallets potentially becoming a
more and more important interface as we move into this decentralized crypto first internet potentially
a contender for the next sort of super app or everything app as jay has argued and i'd also
like to underscore something that you said Brandon which is that crypto is kind of like the black hole
that's that's eating everything else eating traditional finance and and all sorts of other
things we're at a really interesting inflection point right now and it's going to be fascinating
to watch how these trends play out absolutely awesome well thank you guys for coming on the show
and sharing your thoughts yeah thanks so much thanks Brendan